<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Vim | Blog Rudy Lee]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.rudylee.com/categories/vim/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.rudylee.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-12T17:33:38+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.rudylee.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rudy Lee]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rails Engines and Vim]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.rudylee.com/2015/05/03/rails-engines-and-vim/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-03T16:14:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.rudylee.com/2015/05/03/rails-engines-and-vim</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At the moment, I am working on a Ruby on Rails projects using Rails Engines ( you can read more about Rails Engines here: <a href="http://guides.rubyonrails.org/engines.html">http://guides.rubyonrails.org/engines.html</a> ). In this post, I&rsquo;ll share my tips and trick on how to configure your vim to work with Rails Engines.</p>

<h1>NERDTree Bookmark</h1>

<p>I am using NERDTree Bookmark to quickly jump between different engines. If you are using NERDTree, you can create a bookmark by putting your cursor on one of the Rails Engines directory and use the command below:</p>

<p><code>
:Bookmark &lt;engine name&gt;
</code></p>

<p>After you created the bookmark, you can see the bookmarks list by pressing <code>B</code> inside NERDTree window. See the screenshot below:</p>

<p><a href="/images/vim-bookmarks.png"><img src="/images/vim-bookmarks.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>I also added these two options to my vimrc file.</p>

<p><code>
" Automatically show bookmarks list when you open NERDTree
let NERDTreeShowBookmarks=1
let NERDTreeChDirMode=2
</code></p>

<p><code>NERDTreeChDirMode</code> changes the current working directory of your vim to your bookmark directory. This will also enable my favourite rails.vim feature which is open alternate file.</p>

<h1>CtrlP Working Path Mode</h1>

<p>It is normal for Rails Engines to share similar directory structure and filenames. However, this creates problem when you want to search a file using CtrlP plugin. Combined with <code>NERDTreeChDirMode</code>, you can tell CtrlP to search only in the current working directory.</p>

<p>Add this option to your vimrc file to enable this feature:</p>

<p><code>
let g:ctrlp_working_path_mode = 'a'
</code></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for now, I&rsquo;ll update this post if I find a better workflow or configuration. If you are interested, you can check my full vimrc file here: <a href="https://github.com/rudylee/dotfiles/blob/master/vimrc">https://github.com/rudylee/dotfiles/blob/master/vimrc</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
