<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Cooking | Blog Rudy Lee]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.rudylee.com/categories/cooking/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.rudylee.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-12-05T14:48:23+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.rudylee.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rudy Lee]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Curry Noodle]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.rudylee.com/2012/07/08/curry-noodle/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-08T17:43:22+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.rudylee.com/2012/07/08/curry-noodle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week I found video tutorial to cook curry noodle in <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lMrFr8Eh_yM">YouTube</a> and decided to give it a try. Before, I cooked different type of curry (red and green curry ) and always made my own curry paste. The taste wasn&rsquo;t bad but obviously something missing and I don&rsquo;t know what it is.</p>

<p>This weekend I am gonna do something different by using pre-made curry paste. After researching a little bit, I found people recommend to use Mae Ploy Curry Paste which they say is used in some of Thai restaurants in Australia. Here is the picture :</p>

<p><a href="http://blog.rudylee.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/mae-ploy.jpg"><img src="http://blog.rudylee.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/mae-ploy-150x150.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>And here is the complete list of ingredients:</p>

<ul>
<li>Noodle ( any kind of noodle, I am using Hokkien noodle ).</li>
<li>Curry Paste ( Mae Ploy ).</li>
<li>Coconut Milk ( main ingredient ).</li>
<li>Shallot.</li>
<li>Garlic.</li>
<li>Red Onion.</li>
<li>Spring Onion.</li>
<li>Chicken Breast.</li>
<li>Prawns ( quite expensive, $5 for 10 prawns ).</li>
<li>Fried Tofu.</li>
<li>Chili Sauce ( I am using ABC Chili Sauce ).</li>
<li>Lemon Grass.</li>
<li>Hard Boiled Eggs ( optional ).</li>
<li>Shrimp Paste ( I switched dried shrimp in the video with this shrimp paste because the price of dried shrimp is too expensive ).</li>
<li>Sugar and Salt for tasting.</li>
</ul>


<p>I am not gonna explain how to cook it as you can learn it yourself from the video. You don&rsquo;t need to follow all the ingredients and try to experiment with your own style ( which I did ). And here is the final result of my Red Curry without the noodle :</p>

<p><a href="http://blog.rudylee.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/curry.jpg"><img src="http://blog.rudylee.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/curry-150x150.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>The taste is milder than my previous curry ( thanks to the Mae Ploy pre-made curry paste ). Next destination is Thai Green Curry or probably Pad Thai.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
